Isaac A. Liem

23607 West 51<sup>st</sup> Ter. Shawnee, KS 66226 816-589-8376 liemisaac@gmail.com

Creative, technical, experienced data and analytical architect with a passion for research and development. I am a visualization specialist with certifications in PowerBI and Tableau. A background in managing risk-on businesses, I provide immense value in risk appropriations through quantitative analysis. I am a builder of blue-sky opportunities to provide strategic new revenue streams.

Tallan, Inc

Hartford, CT (Remote)

03/2022 – Present Data & Analytics Architect

## **Experience:**

Created innovative solutions using the latest software technology and tools to help companies build for the future and overcome their toughest challenges. As a multiple Gold Competency partner with Microsoft, I strategically worked together with them to identify client needs and accelerate the deployment cloud-based solutions. Using my advanced knowledge of Azure, I've designed and implemented robust solutions for large and medium sized companies globally. Participated and led client facing pre-sales conversations, created SOW's, bids, and timeline schedules.

The Scoular Company

Overland Park, KS

03/2021 - 03/2022 Leader of Innovations & Research (IT)

#### **Experience:**

Created an innovation ecosystem to promote innovative idea generation using gamification across the enterprise. Identified, piloted, and deployed several proof-of-concepts that aligned with challenges set by the company for strategic growth. Created and broadened new division of innovations and emerging business.

03/2019 - 03/2020 Director of Risk (IT)

## **Experience:**

Developed and deployed the Value-at-Risk model for quantifying risk allocations between commodity classes. Built risk reports displaying relevant information to traders, managers, risk personnel, and executives. Develop models and reports quantifying tail risk events and the effect on the firm. Developed risk quantification talent among traders and the broader firm. Quantifying, evaluating, and

articulating company risk to all levels of management through visualization tools such as Tableau and Power BI.

## 06/2018 - 03/2019 Senior Software Engineer

#### **Experience:**

Worked with executives, directors, and C-level creating Mark-to-market, position, profit and loss, accounts receivable and accounts payable, margin reports for different operational business units.

Upgraded and migrated existing infrastructure to Azure Cloud Services (Data Lake) from IBM environment. Managed and directed consulting organization to perform our Enterprise Transformation.

## **DST Pharmacy Solutions Inc. (formerly Argus Health)**

Kansas City, MO

08/2016 - 06/2018 Software Engineer

### **Experience:**

Collaborated with the Chief Medical Officer and other C-level executives to identify use cases for client needs. Deployed Tableau Server across the enterprise. Programmed business model algorithms for identifying high to low-risk chronic disease patients. Created suites of new visualizations, pioneering the company as the go to visualization expert.

### **Axion LLC (Department of Homeland Security Contract)**

Lee's Summit, MO

02/2016 - 08/2016 Senior Data Analyst

#### **Experience:**

Championed Tableau visualization tool and created reports for several business users which allowed them to be more efficient and save time. Generated reports for transitioning contractors that required extensive knowledge of processes and improving turn around for incoming contractors.

## Serco NA (Department of Homeland Security Contract)

Overland Park, KS

11/2012 - 01/2016 Programmer II

#### **Experience:**

Creation of the BETR process which resulted in a stipulation bonus for the closing of Serco's contract and a production increase of up to 60% a day which carried over to the new contract and is used by multiple teams. Created a complex dynamic overtime database for 1,000 users which increased forecasting abilities and tracking for billing government. This saved payroll, managers, supervisors and leads time as this was before a manual process which they no longer had to do.

## **Education:**

# **Bellevue University**

B.S. in Data Science

# **Johnson County Community College**

Computer Science

# **Kearney High School**

Tableau Certified Associate Power BI Certified Associate